CURRICULUM VITAE'

Vibha Mendiratta TGT Physics Teacher (CBSE School)

M.Sc. (Physics)-Gold Medalist Email: ssvibha07@gmail.com
B.Ed., M.Ed. M: +91-9818698601/9818697324

CAREER OBJECTIVE

Compassionate Physics Teacher with twenty years of experience in instructing and guiding the secondary students. Skilled in engaging students in complex topics and creating individualized approaches to education based on each student's strengths and abilities.

To make a mark as the competent Physics Teacher of a reputed School (CBSE). The new job should give me; more responsibilities, better autonomy and challenging opportunities to utilize my more than two decades of experience in teaching to make students better citizens of future.

CAREER EXPERIENCE:

Time Period	Name of School	Number of	Designation
		Years	
July 22 to Till date	Modern Vidya Niketan School,	1 years	Teaching &
	Sector 88, Faridabad , Haryana		Admin
2008 to 2022	Modern Vidya Niketan School,	14 years	TGT Physics
	Aravali Hills, Faridabad , Haryana		-
2000 to 2004	Modern Vidya Niketan School,	4 years	TGT Physics
	Sector 17, Faridabad , Haryana		-
1999 to 2000	Raman Munjal Vidya	1 year	PGT Physics
	Mandir,Gurgaon		

ACADEMIC QUALIFICATION:

Education	Main Subject	University	Year	Remarks
Masters of	Education	Maharishi	2010	Ist Division
Education (M.Ed.)		Dayanand		
		University (MDU)		
Bachelor of	Education	Delhi University	2000	75% and 4 th Rank Holder in
Education (B.Ed.)				University
Masters -M.Sc.	Physics	Maharishi	1999	77% and Gold Medalist
		Dayanand		
		University (MDU)		
Graduation- B.Sc.	Physics,	Maharishi	1997	Ist Division
	Chemistry, Math	Dayanand		
		University (MDU)		

XII	Science	CBSE	1994	78.2%(Blue Bells School,	
				Gurgaon)	

Key Responsibilities:

- > Instruct 8 Sections each of Class IX and X and prepare them for Board Examinations.
- ➤ Taking NTSE & Olympiad classes
- > Perform weekly and monthly evaluations of each student and develop plan for improvement.
- Assign and score daily assignment and monthly/ quarterly exams as per CBSE pattern.
- ➤ Host special remedial classes and test material for students to improve their grades.
- Improve grades of Students on regular basis
- > Identify strategies for improving student achievement and student counselling.
- Organizing & Developing the School clubs like Science club, English club, Information Technology club, dance, Debate clubs etc.

Key Projects Handled:

- Awarded as best teacher in Delhi NCR by Education Minister Smt. Smirti Irani.
- Authored a book on multiple choice questions for class X students for preparing for CBSE examinations.
- Participated in the Physics workshop 'From Conventional to Empirical' by Dr. H.C. Verma-Professor at IIT Kanpur at The Heritage School , Gurgaon
- > Participated and won various inter school science exhibition competitions
- ➤ Won Twice the State Level and National level CBSE Science Exhibitions.
- > Took the class IX & X students to IIT-Delhi for participation in Education Conclave.
- Taking career workshops for students from class VIII- X
- > One of the member of committee to prepare award list of class X students during Covid period

Basic Personal skills:

Patience | Compassion | Communication | Curriculum planning | Independent study development | Science instruction | Innovative | Result oriented | Team Player

PERSONAL DETAILS:

Year of Birth : December 1977

Marital Status : Married

Current Location : Faridabad (NCR Delhi), Haryana